

AYRAT ZAYNUTDINOV Data Analyst

Moscow, Russian Federation **Email**: <u>ayratzay@gmail.com</u> **Mobile**: +7 999 999-14-03 **Telegram/Skype**: ayratzay

Nationality: Russian English: Advanced

Going to relocate with common-law wife

Marital status: Single

Salary expectation: 2300 EURO net Ready to relocate ASAP.

Data Analyst with 5+ years' experience. Technical strength includes MS BI, Data Studio, Tableau, SQL, Hadoop, Python, R, JS. Interested in projects were he can implement his BI skills and knowledge of business processes.

Highly interested in relocation to Europe. Willing to develop in BI field, also interested in Machine Learning and Data Science.

SKILLS

Experience with Analytical frameworks and services

- AppsFlyer, Facebook Analytics, Google Analytics, Firebase Analytics, GameAnalytics
- Data Studio, Tableau, MS BI
- Big Query, SQL, Hadoop, MongoDB
- Python libraries: Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, xgboost, Keras
- Data Modeling: Frequentist Statistics, Bayesian Statistics, Hidden Markov Models, Random Forest, Survival Analysis
- Google Tag Manager

Programming languages

comfortable with: Python

have experience in: JavaScript, Octave, R

Other computer skills

bash, git, Google Cloud Platform (AppEngine, Compute Engine, Storage, Dataflow), Docker, Kubernetes, Apache Beam

Languages

	Russian - native
	English - full professional proficiency
	Turkish - fluent
П	Korean - basic survival level

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Analyst, Cryptology

March. 2018 - Oct. 2018



- **Data collecting.** Creating data pipeline from service core into analytical data base in a scalable manner. Appending various external data sources inside one analytical database.
- **ETL.** Data transformation, creating aggregate tables for data storage efficiency and query costs optimization
- **BI service.** Creating reports and dashboards using BI tools based on business needs of other departments
- **Anomalies.** Tracking for anomalies in metrics and dashboard data. Creating alerts if anomaly is detected

Data Analyst, Leto45

Oct. 2017 - March 2018

- **Data collecting, storing, processing and visualization**. I was for responsible for data collecting from users and storing their data in databases. After data was stored, it was processed with routine scripts for creating summarizing statistics for various periods. I set daily check-up dashboards
- **Business insights.** Searching for business insights in data and with the cooperation of other departments trying to optimize current business processes
- Business modeling. Supporting business decisions with models based on historical data

Data analyst, AST222 games

Feb. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Started project from the scratch. I formed scheme for data storage, documentation for data collection on client side for developers. Formed reporting patterns for reporting routine
- General statistics including retention, LTV, regs, etc
- Comparing game mechanics and financial performance of modifications made on a new versions to current version
- Creating funnels and analyzing drop-offs
- User/session clustering based on user activities

Internet Marketing Analyst, Veeam Software

Nov. 2013 - Aug. 2015

- Making monthly and yearly targets on web site visitors
- Integrating SalesForce data to Google Analytics
- Setting web site tracking using Google Tag Manager
- Reporting automation from CRM database

Purchasing Specialist, Kompas Engineering

Dec. 2012 - April 2013

- Purchasing supplies for construction
- Documentation translation English/Turkish/Russian

Purchasing Specialist, Samsung Electronics Rus Kaluga

Sept. 2012 - Nov. 2012

- Purchasing packing materials from local vendors
- Purchasing electrical supplies from East and South East Asian Vendors
- Short and middle term purchasing planning
- Shipment and stock control



COMPETENCE AND INTERESTS

Mentionable projects on Kaggle

Trying to predict sales in over 500 stores in German drug store chain Rossmann. Sales prediction made in based on 3 years' sales, store characteristics. Predictions are made using Random Forest.

EDUCATION

Yeungjin College, South Korea Aug. 2010 – Aug. 2011 School of Electronics and Info-Communications Associated Degree of Engineering (Yeungjin-Samsung Electronics Program)

Dokuz Eylul University, Turkey

Sept. 2005 - Jun. 2010

Faculty of Economics and Administrative Science, Public Finance Bachelor of Arts in Public Finance (Research on Asian Tigers (South Korea))